[
    {
        "front": "つけます ❘",
        "back": "turn on",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "けします ❘",
        "back": "turn off",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "あけます❘❘",
        "back": "open",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "しめます❘❘",
        "back": "close, shut",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "いそぎます ❘",
        "back": "hurry",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "まちます❘",
        "back": "wait",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "とめます❘❘",
        "back": "stop, park",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "まがります❘\n「みぎへ～」",
        "back": "turn [to the right]",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "もちます ❘",
        "back": "hold",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "とります ❘",
        "back": "take, pass",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "てつだいます ❘",
        "back": "help (with a task)",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "よびます ❘",
        "back": "call",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "はなします ❘",
        "back": "speak, talk",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "みせます ❘❘",
        "back": "show",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "おしえます ❘❘\n[じゅうしょを～]",
        "back": "tell [an address]",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "はじめます ❘❘",
        "back": "start, begin",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "ふります ❘❘\n「あめが」",
        "back": "rain",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "コピーします ❘❘❘",
        "back": "copy",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "エアコン",
        "back": "air conditioner",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "パスポート",
        "back": "passport",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "なまえ",
        "back": "name",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "じゅうしょ",
        "back": "address",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "ちず",
        "back": "map",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "しお",
        "back": "salt",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "さとう",
        "back": "sugar",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "よみかた",
        "back": "how to read, way of reading",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "～かた",
        "back": "how to ~, way of ‘ing",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "ゆっくり",
        "back": "slowly, leisurely",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "すぐ",
        "back": "immediately",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "また",
        "back": "again",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "あとで",
        "back": "later",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "もう すこし",
        "back": "a little more",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "もう",
        "back": "~more, another~",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "いいですよ",
        "back": "Sure / Certainly",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "さあ",
        "back": "(used when encouraging some course of action)",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "あれ？",
        "back": "Oh! (In surprise or in wonder)",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "しんごうを みぎへ まがって ください",
        "back": "Turn to at the signal",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "まっすぐ",
        "back": "straight",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "これで おねがいします",
        "back": "I’d like to pay with this",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "おつり",
        "back": "Change",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    },
    {
        "front": "くすり",
        "back": "medicine",
        "chapter": "N5 C14"
    }
]